Guide to the Jimmy Creech Papers, 1972-2014 RL.11114
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Activist Work, 2
  - Engagements, 3
    - Southern Baptist Convention, St. Louis, 2002 June 8-12 (Box 7)
    - Calendar, 2011 (Box 7)
    - Syracuse University, NY, 2011 April 7-9 (Box 7)
    - Trinity UMC, Austin, TX, 2011 May 6-9 (Box 7)
    - IDAHO, Paris, France, 2011 May 17-23 (Box 7)
    - The Normal Heart NYC, 2011 May 23-25 (Box 7)
    - California, 2001 June 10-20 (Box 7)
    - University of Illinois of Springfield, 2011 October 4-6 (Box 7)
    - Nebraska, 2011 October 11-16 (Box 8)
    - Birmingham, Alabama, 2011 October 26-27 (Box 8)
    - Foundry, UMC, Washington, DC, 2011 September 23-26 (Box 8)
    - Upstate Pride and Unitarian Universalist Church, Spartanburg, SC, 2011 June 4-5; 1 folder (Box 8)
    - Northaven UMC, Dallas, TX, 2011 November 1-2 (Box 8)
    - Salt Lake City, Utah, 2011 November 4-6 (Box 8)
    - UUF/Peace UCC, Clemson, SC, 2012 January 29 (Box 8)
    - Colgate Rochester Croger Divinity School, 2012 February 21 (Box 8)
    - Boston University, 2012 March 6-7 (Box 8)
    - Little Rock, AR, 2012 September 21-23 (Box 8)
    - Columbia, SC, 2012 October 19-21 (Box 8)
    - Rehoboth Beach, DE, 2012 November 16-18 (Box 8)
    - New Dimensions, Acton, Massachusetts, 2012 October 12-13 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 8)
    - Open Door Metropolitan Community Church Sunday Worship Service with Jimmy Creech, 2000 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL-11114-VHS-0001)
      Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of use copies. To request access to these items, please contact Research Services in advance of your research visit.
    - Larry King Live, 2000 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL-11114-VHS-0002)
    - Amanda Lamb WRAL-TV, Interview with Larry Ellis and Jim, 1999 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL-11114-VHS-0003)
    - A Union in Wait (Box 10, Video-cassette RL-11114-VHS-0004)
    - Omaha TV, 1999 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL-11114-VHS-0005)
    - Jimmy Creech (Box 10, Video-cassette RL-11114-VHS-0006)
    - In My Father's Church (Box 10, Video-cassette RL-11114-VHS-0007)
    - Jimmy Creech at the Church of the Good Shepherd United Church of Christ (Box 11, Dvd RL-11114-DVD-00003)
    - "Coming Home for the First Time," Metropolitan Community Church Los Angeles (Box 11, Dvd RL-11114-DVD-0002)
    - FUMC Omaha RMN 10th Anniversary (Box 11, Dvd RL-11114-DVD-00001)
    - Speaking Engagements Emails, 1998-2001; 7 3.5 floppy discs containing 299 files; less than 1 MB (Digital-materials RL11114-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
      Emails in html in rfc822 formats. One floppy disc (RL11114-FL3-0044) may included partially damaged and unreadable files.
  - RRNGLE (Raleigh Religious Network for Gay and Lesbian Equality), 4
    Raleigh Religious Network for Gay and Lesbian Equality (RRNGLE) subseries contains files given to Creech by member Patricia Long. Files include organizational history and meeting minutes, printed material, and correspondence. Contains correspondence from Long's attempt to publish a book about the organization.
    Audio tapes with interviews of RRNGLE members also provided by Patricia Long.
    - Conference Planning: Hotel, undated (Box 8)
    - Grant Proposal SECLGM, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE Resources, undated (Box 8)
    - Evaluations, 1988-1993 (Box 8)
    - Registrations, 1991-1992, 1998 (Box 8)
    - Fundraising Materials, undated (Box 8)
    - Letters with Contributions, undated (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE Organizational History, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE Conference, 1994 (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE Correspondence, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE Notes, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8)
    - New N.C. Networks, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE Outreach, undated (Box 8)
    - Meeting Notes, 1989 July - 1992 February (Box 8)
    - Other Great Proposals, Grant Information, undated (Box 8)
    - Speeches, Workshops, undated (Box 8)
    - Resource Guide, undated (Box 8)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 8)
    - Outreach Coordination, undated (Box 8)
    - Gays, Lesbians, and Religious Communities, undated (Box 8)
    - Media Reactions and Responses, undated (Box 8)
    - Personal Stories, Nelson, 1991 (Box 8)
    - Jimmy Creech, undated (Box 8)
    - Report: Originals and Extras, undated (Box 8)
    - Memoranda and Meeting Minutes, undated (Box 8)
    - Publishers, Correspondence, undated (Box 8)
    - Outline, undated (Box 8)
    - Hearings and Formation of RRNGLE, undated (Box 8)
    - "My First RRNGLE Meeting", undated (Box 8)
    - Heroes/Mentors, undated (Box 8)
    - Husted House, undated (Box 8)
    - Community UCC, undated (Box 8)
    - Outreach, Events, undated (Box 8)
    - Other Groups, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE as Ecumenical, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE as Community, undated (Box 8)
    - Future Outreach, undated (Box 8)
    - Particular Denominations, undated (Box 8)
    - Race, undated (Box 8)
    - Being Out, undated (Box 8)
    - Empowering Risk Taking, undated (Box 8)
    - Why Religious, undated (Box 8)
    - Other Peace and Justice Issues, undated (Box 8)
    - Retreats, "Foolies," Picnics, Party, undated (Box 8)
    - Breakfast Meetings, undated (Box 8)
    - Speeches and Workshops, undated (Box 8)
    - Duke, undated (Box 8)
    - RRNGLE Conferences, General, undated (Box 8)
    - Pride Marches, undated (Box 9)
    - Personal Stories, Fulkerson, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Personal Stories, McNeill, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Beverly Harrison, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Youth, Hope, God, undated (Box 9)
    - Holy Unions, undated (Box 9)
    - Clergy Outreach Events, undated (Box 9)
    - Other N.C Networks, undated (Box 9)
    - Media: Sojourners, radio, undated (Box 9)
    - Issues, undated (Box 9)
    - How to: Networking, undated (Box 9)
    - How to: Conferences, undated (Box 9)
    - How to: Small Groups, undated (Box 9)
    - How to: Congregation, undated (Box 9)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 9)
    - Resources, undated (Box 9)
    - Sermons by RRNGLE Members, undated (Box 9)
    - Letters to editor by RRNGLE Members, undated (Box 9)
    - Writings by RRNGLE Members, undated (Box 9)
    - Sermons by Others, undated (Box 9)
    - Newspaper and Magazine Articles about RRNGLE, undated (Box 9)
    - RRNGLE Resources, undated (Box 9)
    - Meetings and Notes, 1 folder (Box 9)
    - Funding Exchange, Out Fund, undated (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Accounting for Fundraising, undated (Box 9)
    - Letterhead, undated (Box 9)
    - Interview List and Topics, undated (Box 9)
    - Brochures, undated (Box 9)
    - Meeting Notes, 1989-1993 (Box 9)
    - First Conference, Fulkerson, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Fourth Conference, Nelson, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Fifth Conference, McNeill, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Sixth Conference, Hamson, 1993 (Box 9)
    - RRNGLE interview Jimmy Creech (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0001)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 3 and 4 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-1114-CS-0002)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 9 and 10 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0003)
    - RRNGLE interviews, side 11 and 12 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0004)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 14 and 15 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0005)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 17 and 18 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0006)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 19 and 20 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0007)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 23 and 24 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0008)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 25 and 26 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0009)
    - RRNGLE interview side 27 and 28 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0010)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 29 and 30 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0011)
    - RRNGLE interviews side 31 and 32 (Box 12, Audio-cassette RL-11114-CS-0012)
  - Subject Files of Organizations, People, and Causes
    - God in the Shadow of Death, undated (Box 6)
    - The migrant work camp, undated (Box 6)
    - Orlando, FLA/SBC, 2000 June 13-16 (Box 6)
    - Karen Damman's Trial Seattle, WA, 2004 March 15-19 (Box 6)
    - New Tactics in Human Rights Project International/Symposium, September 29 - October 3, 1999 (Box 6)
    - Statement Re. Public Safety Death Penalty, undated (Box 6)
    - Greenville, SC, undated (Box 6)
    - Hickory / Taylorsville, undated (Box 6)
    - Death penalty vigils, undated (Box 6)
    - Phillip Ingle, 1995 (Box 6)
    - Ames, Iowa, undated (Box 6)
    - Ted Haggard, undated (Box 6)
    - Methodist Foundation for Social Action (MFSA ) - National support, undated (Box 6)
    - Laity group / opposition, undated (Box 6)
    - David Lawson, 1994-1997 (Box 6)
    - Email Correspondence, 1997 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence with Susan Davies, 1996 Spring (Box 6)
    - Fred Phelps, undated (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous communications, undated (Box 6)
    - Soulforce interview with Mel White, 1998 February (Box 6)
    - Judicial Council Decision, undated (Box 6)
    - Faith in America, undated (Box 6)
    - Faith in America - Talking Points, undated (Box 6)
    - Thinking it Through, undated (Box 6)
    - Media Coverage, after 2000 (Box 6)
    - Sacramento 68, 1999 (Box 6)
      The Sacramento 68 referes to 68 Methodist clergy members who were accused of violating the order and discipline of the United Methodist Church by participating in a same-sex union service for two women in Sacramento, California on January, 16 1999.
    - "Why We Officiated at a Service of Holy Union", 1999; 1 folder (Box 6)
    - Greg Dell's Trial, 1999; 1 folder (Box 6)
    - Dell, Greg, 1999 (Box 6)
    - With Love newletters, 1998-2003 (Box 6)
    - Bread articles, undated (Box 6)
      "Bread" newsletter published by First United Methodist Church Omaha
    - Clifton United Methodist Church, Cincinnati, OH, 1999 May 11 (Box 6)
    - Press coverage and correspondence with journalists, 1998-2000 (Box 6)
    - Human Rights Campaign - Religion Report, 1998 (Box 6)
    - General Conference of the United Methodist Church, 2000 (Box 6)
    - NC Marriage Amendment, 2004-2011 (Box 6)
    - Soulforce at General Conference, 2000 (Box 6)
    - Committee on Investigation for Clergy members, California/Nevada Annual Conference, undated (Box 7)
    - Reverend Irene Monroe, 2000 (Box 7)
    - NCARRV: North Carolinians Against Racist and Religious Violence, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Printed materials, 2000-2011 (Box 7)
    - Newspaper articles, 2012-2014 (Box 7)
    - Fenceberry Articles, 1999-2000; 3 3.5 inch floppy discs containing 80 files; less than 1 MB (Digital-materials RL11114-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
      LGBT news service articles in html and rfc822 formats.
    - Soulforce Journey, 1999; 1 3.5 inch floppy disk containing 21 files; less than 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL11114-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
      Emails about LGBT experience and activism in html format.
- Writings, 3
  The Writings series contains articles, sermons, research files, and other written material generated by Creech throughout his career. The bulk of the series consists of drafts of his memoir Adam's Gift, originally entitled The Church on Trial, and materials related to its publication in 2011.
  - Research Files, 5
    - Homosexuality and Religion, 1992-1997 (Box 9)
    - Report of the Committee to Study Homosexuality, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
    - Anti-Gay Violence, undated (Box 9)
    - Anatomy of Oppression, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Sermons, Articles, and Miscellaneous Writings
    - The Lie of Violence; The Truth of Love, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Methodist Experience in America, undated (Box 9)
    - Sermons, Homilies, and Reflections on the Death Penalty, undated (Box 9)
    - Sermons/Talks, 2000-2012 (Box 9)
    - Quest Article, Born to be Lovers, 2012-2013 (Box 9)
    - Articles, 1997, 1999 and undated (Box 9)
    - Rise Above the Law, 1999 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1967-2012 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1996-2000 (Box 11)
  - Adam's Gift, 6
    Contains drafts and publication information about Creech's memoir Adam's Gift, published by Duke University Press in 2011.
    - Correspondence and News Articles, 1 folder (Box 9)
    - Publishers, 1 folder (Box 9)
    - Interviews, Omaha, 2002-2005; 1 folder (Box 9)
    - Drafts, Introduction - Ch. 6, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Drafts, Ch. 7-20, 11 folders (Box 10)
    - Book Backup #1 and Miscellaneous Material, 2001-2002; 1 3.5 inch floppy disc containing 11 files; less than 1 MB (Digital-materials RL11114-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
      Document files in Lotus Word Pro format. There is one document in AMI Professional format. Documents include drafts, a proposal, and an outline for Adam's Gift. There are also interviews and transcripts about gay marriage.
  - Writings by Others, 7
    Writings by others series contains published articles sent to Creech by their authors as well as drafts and manuscripts of writings by others sent to Creech.
    - Keith Hartman/Fairmount UMC, 1996 (Box 10)
    - Partrick Colatch's Paper, undated (Box 10)
    - Religious Roots of Violence, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1998-1999 (Box 10)
    - Horace Griffin, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Homosexuality: An attempt at dialogue, Willie E. Frye, 1993 (Box 11)